Researchers use tiny lab grown human
brains to operate a dogbot and give it
sensory feedback. This technology may
provide a foundation for biohybrid
robotics as well as allow us to
interface with our neurons directly so
that we can have sensory feedback. Now,
piloting a dog bot is not the central
point of the paper, but I think it's
really cool. Brain organoids are being
used to run simulations like this in
which they have to navigate because it
gives us information about how brains
function. If you wanted to study
Alzheimer's, for example, if it degraded
and failed to run Dogbot, that could be
an indication. Now, normally in this
field, if they wanted to do something
like this, they would need something
called opsson genetics. They've
implanted tiny human brains that have
been genetically engineered to react
when light is shined on them. So, they
have a way to control them. In the case
of Dogbot, they didn't require that. No,
they grew brain organoids directly onto
a layer of graphine. And graphine is
unique because it can take signals and
turn them directly into information that
a neuron can read. So they can be
directly interfaced. Now technology like
this has been used to give robot
sensation like taste because it can take
sensory feedback and turn it directly
into electrical activity. And of course,
it could be used to give robots a very
high resolution sense of touch. That is
important for, you know, having robots
that are able to interact with the
world, but it could also be used for
prosthetics, but also robots that could
interact with the world like Puppy Pi 4
that was used in the UC San Diego lab.
This is a commercially available robot,
and they're not that expensive, and I am
seriously thinking of getting one. They
use LAR, so as it approaches an
obstacle, it sends that information back
to the brain organoid. It's filtered and
then that brain organoid can then
respond to it and they do learn. We are
seeing a robot that has sensation. It
has been claimed that the brain
organoids are sentient because they're
capable of having an experience. They
can be taught on ordered and disordered
signals. They like order. I've even seen
papers and talked about papers in which
they're given continuous electric shocks
till they do what they want them to do
in Pac-Man. They seem to do better just
from what I've read when they're given
both positive reinforcement, so ordered
signals and dopamine burst as well as
negative reinforcement rather than just
one or the other. But they can learn on
them one or the other. This kind of
technology is so important in several
different areas. It's great for medical
research. If we can see how a brain is
reacting to spatial environments, it
unlocks a whole new area of studying
people, you know, people that are not in
a human body. Traditional LLMs are just
not good with spatial information.
They're not good at operating a body in
the world, especially not a soft body,
but brain organoids can. Even
neuromorphic brain organoids that are
just programmed and not actually
physical or better at operating in three
dimensions. It gives us an interface for
which we could use for our own medicine.
Think robotic eyes. Think robotic
tongues is apparently possible. And of
course, limbs that have a real sense of
touch. And of course, you know me, I'm
hoping for conscious machines. I don't
think it's a good idea to make conscious
machines, but I do think it's possible,
and I kind of want to see it happen. I
know that's not very responsible of